

# APEL MAHMUD

## Frontend Developer

Junior Software Developer specializing in front-end development with 1 year professional experience in employing functional programming to build web projects. Software Engineering graduate skilled in JavaScript and React framework demonstrated expertise improving workflow efficiency and driving user engagement. Proficent in Responsive design and technical specification and also experienced with backend technology.

Location: Dhaka, Bangladesh | Phone: +8801303451038

**Email:** apelmahmud1151@gmail.com | **Web:** https://apelmahmud1151.netlify.app

### **EDUCATION**

Yunnan University

Kunming, China

Bachelor of Engineering

Sep 2018- July 2022

Major in Software Engineering

CGPA: 2.67/4.0

Relevant Coursework: Software Engineering; Operating Systems; Algorithms; Web; System Design

Govt. Azizul Haque College

Bogura, Bangladesh

Higher Secondary School(H.S.C)

Jul 2015 - Jul 2017

Science CGPA:4.83/5

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Inleads IT (Software Company) Software Development Intern Bogura, Bangladesh

July 2021 - Oct 2021

- Cooperate with developers to create clean interfaces and simple, intuitive interactions.
- Complete detailed programming and development tasks for front-end and internal websites as well aschallenging back-end server code. I've learned more about backend technology such as Node.js, Express.js, API, Mongodb database, Sql in this peroid.
- Handle errors and optimize usability Contact: Arifur Rahman, CO Founder, Inleads IT- www.linkedin.com/in/arifsclick

Flora Systems Limited (Software Company)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Jan 2023 - Present

Software Support Engineer

- Research and identify solutions to software, Database and application.
- Taking any kind of software issues from bankers and resolve them or provide to the development team. Testingdatabase, server, and payment of Internet Banking in different Banks.
- Sql query in system database for any changes or findings.
- Cooperate with senior developers to create different frontend components and states.

Contact: Mizanul Haque, AGM, Support, Flora System Ltd - mizan.ftl@gmail.com

### PERSONAL PROJECTS

Quiz App With Timer

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

**Functional Todo Application** 

Technologies: HTML, CSS, BootStrap, React

**Responsive Multipage Website (frontend)** Technologies: HTML, CSS/SAAS, Vanilla Js

Mern-Stack E-commerce Website

Technologies: React, Node, REST api, Mongodb

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

### DEVELOPED MULTIPLE FRONTEND WEBSITES

- Beautiful Service Website
- Responsive Doctor's Portal Website

### COLABORATED WITH A COMPLETE WEB APPLICATION EMPLOYEE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

• Employee Management System (web application)

# **ADDITIONAL**

**Technical Skills**: C, **Javascript**, **HTML/CSS**, SQL, **React**, Node, Monogdb, REST API, Express, Redux, Next.js **Languages**: Fluent in **English**; Conversational Proficiency in **Chinese**. **Bengali** is Native.

#### **Certifications & Training**

- \* Responsive Web Design
- ❖ JavaScripts Data-Stracture and Algorithm ☑
- Frontend Development Libraries
- Technical Support Fundamental

Tools: VS code, SSMS, Github, Postmon

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/apel1151/
- https://github.com/apel1151

**Md Apel Mahmud**